MORGAN OHENE ASARE

■ MOBILE: +447946061501 ■ ohenemorgan@gmail.com

PERSONAL SUMMARY

Morgan is an IT enthusiast who holds a Bachelor Degree in Telecommunications Engineering and Masters in Computing. He has a wide range of experience both in Information Technology and Telecommunication Engineering field. Currently, He works as a Technical Support Engineer with excellent knowledge in QMS, SAP ERP and IT infrastructure.

EDUCATION

De Montfort University - Leicester, England (2017-2018)

Master of Science: Computing

Courses Studied: Human Factors in System Design, E-Commerce Software (ASP.NET in C#), E-Commerce Systems Research, Ethics and Professionalism in Computing, Object Oriented Programming (Java), Data Base Systems and Designs, Computer Systems and Network, Systems Analysis and Design.

Ghana Technology University College, Accra (2012-2014)

Bachelor of Science: Telecommunications Engineering

Courses Studied: Data communication, Digital Signal Processing, Communication Electronics, Basic Accounting, Communication Networks and Antenna Propagation, Electromagnetic Compatibility, Mobile and Satellite Communication, Optical Fibre Communications, Emerging Technologies.

Ghana Technology University College, Accra (2009-2012)

Diploma: Telecommunications Engineering

Courses Studied: Data communication, Digital Signal Processing, Communication Electronics, Communication Networks and Antenna Propagation, Electromagnetic Compatibility, Mobile and Satellite.

Armed Forces Senior High School- Kumasi (2005-2008)

Courses Studied: Building Construction

PROFESSIONAL COURSES

SAP Certified Technology Associate – System Administration (SAP HANA) with NetWeaver 7.5 (2021)

Modules: SAP Systems Concept, Database Administration, System Administration, SAP Fiori, Transport Management, Installation and Patching SAP Systems.

SAP Business Process Integration S/4 HANA (2020)

Modules: SAP ERP Basics and Navigation, SAP Accounting Basics, Purchase to Pay Process in ERP/Fiori, Plan to Produce Process SAP ERP/Fiori, Order to Cash SAP ERP/Fiori.

SAP ACTIVATE PROJECT MANAGEMENT (2020)

Modules: Agile Delivery Approach, Agile Project Planning, New Implementation SAP S/4HANA Cloud Concepts, Selective Data Transition Concepts, System Conversion Concepts.

Admin Telecom Academy, Accra (2014)

Certificate: Fibre Optics and Microwave Transmission

Modules: Network overview, Microwave system overview, Microwave configuration, Fusion splicing, Testing light power meter, Optical fibre cable enclosure, Testing OTDR

WORK HISTORY

Software Support Engineer (03/2023 - Present)

CST Pharma Limited

- Acting as the main specialist of the Electronic Quality Management system (resolving and responding to teams via phone and email)
- Maintaining the health of the database by monitoring the storage availability
- Write basic SQL queries to retrieve data from the database
- Documenting SOP's of modules in the eQMS application
- Training the eQMS application administrators on best practices
- Writing Work instruction on how to use various (especially eQMS and V-Soft) in-house applications
- Raising change control request for major and minor changes on the eQMS system
- Review Quality Management System Documentation
- Liaising between CST Pharma and external IT support companies to resolve system related issues
- Act as the project coordinator for Quality Management system upgrades
- Creating simple excel formulas for different departments

Technical Support Engineer (06/2022 – 03/2023)

Ideagen Company

- Q-Pulse (Quality)Installation
- Q-Pulse Administration (On-premise / Cloud)
- Database Installation (SQL)
- Database Backup / Database Restore
- Troubleshooting
- Remote Support (Phone calls and Remote Sessions)

SAP Technical Consultant (10/2020 – 02/2022)

Persol Systems Limited

- S/4HANA 1909 Installation and Upgrade
- Installation of Databases (HANA/SQL)
- System Monitoring
- Business One Administration (On-premise / Cloud)

- Installation of SAP Business One
- Suse Linux Administration
- Database Backup and Recovery
- Customer service
- Remote Support

Systems Administrator (01/2019 - 05/2019)

Nsano Ghana Ltd.

- Daily systems availability monitoring
- Application configuration and deployment
- Backup management
- Software installation and updates
- Active Directory Management
- Website deployment
- System inventory keeping

Convergent Billing Engineer (11/2014 – 02/2016)

Millicom Ghana (Tigo) - Accra

- Short code configuration on CBS.
- Configuration of Post-paid / Prepaid and Hybrid Products on CBS.
- Providing solutions to problems encountered with post-paid, hybrid and prepaid subs.
- Performing general node checks to make sure there is system is availability

PABX Technician (2012 – 2013)

Ministry of Defence (National Service) - Accra

- Routine checks to produce a reliable PABX system.
- Worked on fax machines.
- Networking
- Recording and interpreting results and presenting to supervisor

PERSONAL SKILLS

- Appreciable programming skills (java, c#)
- Knowledge in Linux systems.
- knowledge in SQL, Oracle.
- Working knowledge in Microsoft Word,
 Microsoft Excel, Microsoft Power Point and
 Windows.
- Good communication skills.

- Writing Documentation
- Tutoring
- Product Testing
- Time Management
- Hardware Evaluation
- Data management

Reference: Available upon request.